<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Abhishek Hegde</title>
    <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Abhishek Hegde</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project IX: IPL Data Viz using Tableau</title>
      <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-9/</guid>
      <description>The Indian Premier League, or IPL, is a T20 cricket league, which was founded in 2008 and is held every year. It sees participation from both national and international players, and eight teams representing eight Indian cities compete with each other in a double round-robin format in the league stages, which are followed by playoffs. Over the years, IPL has become one of the most-watched and most attended live sporting events all over the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project VIII: Advanced Regression Techniques for Prediction of House Prices</title>
      <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>Business Understanding and Problem Description: A US-based housing company has decided to enter the Australian market. The company uses data analytics to purchase houses at a price below their actual values and flip them at a higher price. For the same purpose, the company has collected a data set from the sale of houses in Australia. The company is looking at prospective properties to buy to enter the market.
Our Job: We are required to build a regression model using advanced techniques like Iterative Imputation and Transformation for data wrangling; and Ridge/Lasso/ElasticNet Regularisation for modelling in order to predict the actual value of the prospective properties and decide whether to invest in them or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project VII: Lead Scoring using Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>The problem statement of the case study revolved around an education company named X Education that sells online courses to industry professionals. X Education faced a problem of getting a lot of leads, but the lead conversion rate being very poor. To make this process more efficient, the company wishes to identify the most potential leads, also known as ‘Hot Leads’.
X Education appointed us to help them select the most promising leads, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project VI: Clustering of Countries</title>
      <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>HELP International is an international humanitarian NGO that is committed to fighting poverty and providing the people of backward countries with basic amenities and relief during the time of disasters and natural calamities. It runs a lot of operational projects from time to time along with advocacy drives to raise awareness as well as for funding purposes.
After the recent funding programs, they have been able to raise around $ 10 million.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project V: Loan Default Risk Analysis using EDA</title>
      <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to give us an idea of applying EDA in a real business scenario. In this project, apart from applying EDA techniques , we will also develop a basic understanding of risk analytics in banking and financial services and understand how data is used to minimize the risk of losing money while lending to customers.
The loan providing companies find it hard to give loans to the people due to their insufficient or non-existent credit history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project IV: Titanic Survival Prediction Web-App</title>
      <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Designed a web-app which, on entering the details of an imaginary passenger (i.e. name, age, gender, socio-economic class, etc.) tells whether your passenger would have survived the catastrophe or not using the help of an ML algorithm (Random Forrest). Used Heroku for deployment Used Streamlit for UI design.  Link to Web-App 
Link to GitHub Repo
Tags:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project III: Demand Forecasting using MLR</title>
      <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>We are required to model the demand for shared bikes with the available independent variables. It will be used by the management to understand how exactly the demands vary with different features. They can accordingly manipulate the business strategy to meet the demand levels and meet the customer&amp;rsquo;s expectations. Further, the model will be a good way for management to understand the demand dynamics of a new market, helping solve two potential problems for the company:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project II: Dog Breed Image Classifier using CNN and Transfer Learning</title>
      <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>A Project completed as part of Deep Learning Nanodegree by Udacity.
  Built a Deep Learning Pipeline to process the real world ,user-supplied images. Given an image of a dog, the algorithm will identify an estimate of the canine’s breed. If supplied an image of a human, the code will identify the resembling dog breed.
  The CNN model which was built from scratch achieved a Test Accuracy of 16% with a Limited and imbalanced dataset (With this data, it is even difficult for humans to correctly identify the breed of the dog).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project I: Autonomous Self Driving Car</title>
      <link>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ash-code007.github.io/Data-Science-Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>B.E Capstone Project:  Autonomous driving has been a topic of discussion in companies from many years. It has always been promised that this innovation can bring life-changing safety and ease to the otherwise prosaic life of the people. Although something truly driverless is practically nowhere in sight of being available to consumers, it definitely is closer than many think. Current estimates speculate that the world in 2025 will see over a hundred thousand self-driving cars on road, and by 2035 that number would have sky-rocketed to almost 21 million.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>